irene lidia wang

experience designer

irenelidiawang.com irenelidiawang@gmail.com 07923565761 London, UK

Coming from a background in the arts, I am a highly creative and innovative Product Designer with high proficiencies in problem-solving, visual UI design, UX design, UX research, HCI, user-centred design principles and methodologies, product development and agile scrum.

Work Experience

Riverside SW Engineering / UX UI Designer

Nov 2019 - Present, London (UK)

Currently, I collaborate closely with the development team to create javascript prototypes for software products and services. My responsibilities include heuristic analysis, wireframes, sitemaps, user flows, concept sketches and visual design.

Avasarshala / UX UI Intern

July 2020, Remote Work

I redesigned the UI visual style of a kids mobile app. I performed a design audit, presented design suggestions - producing wireframes/mockups - and conducted user tests to validate design solutions. I also worked with an illustrator to complete the project.

Sotheby's Auction House / Assistant

May 2019 - Nov 2019, London (UK)

Thanks to this experience, I learnt how to empathise with people and understand their goals and pain points by conducting customer interviews. I also acquired knowledge of how to create a pleasant, productive and memorable customer experience.

Phillips Auction House / Research Intern

Oct 2018 - May 2019, London (UK)

During this experience, I honed my research skills by conducting secondary and competitive research. I also gained expertise in communicating effectively and concisely with internal and external stakeholders.

UX UI Projects

Skincare Quiz / E-commerce website

View the case study

VIPrivé / E-commerce website

View the case study

KidsClub / Children Mobile App

View the case study

Education

Springboard / UX UI Design Certificate

2019 - 2020

Oxford University / MSt Art History

2017 - 2018

UCL / BA Art History

2014 - 2017

Skills

- Visual UI Design
- UX Research
- Prototyping
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking
- Information Architecture
- Agile Scrum
- Branding (Identity)
- Sketch, Figma, Adobe Creative Suite
- Invision, Keynote
- HTML/CSS/JS
- Empathy and Communication
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- Customer Engagement